Artem Zhukov CV

<https://github.com/ZhukovGreen>

Czech Republic, Roznov pod Radhostem zhukovgreen@icloud.com +420774081898

Software engineer and machine learning engineer with more than 4 years of experience.

Interested in building web applications and bots, complimented with machine learning, growing as a professional, learning new technologies, experimenting and building interesting products.

Tech stack

- web, web applications, microservices, api, bots
- python, aiohttp, numpy, pandas, scipy, pytorch, keras, scikit-learn, xgboost, opencv, freecad, aiogram
- linux, shell, git, docker, gitlab, postgresql, redis, openapi, swagger
- vim, pycharm

Free time

I contribute to open-source projects (i.e. < https://github.com/crθhn/aiohttp-cache, < https://github.com/webknjaz/docker-freecad-cli,), writing telegram bots (i.e. < https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/gcal_time_track_tg_bot,), testing different neural nets architectures and learning new things.

Experience

System Architect | Machine learning engineer | Software team leader at Remak

Dates Employed Jan 2016 - Jan 2020

Employment Duration 4 yrs 1 mos

Building a software platform to support new products and the company's processes.

- leading the team of 4 developers, learning from them
- determining backend architecture and technological stack
- building microservices (Python, aiohttp, Docker, openAPI ...)
- setting up CI pipelines for microservices
- unit and integrational tests and deployment to the staging server
- setting up app monitoring
- applying machine learning techniques to improve user experience.

Particularly speeding up the calculation processes (supervise learning, mostly with gradient boosting, applying optimization with evolutionary algorithms)

HVAC (heating, ventilation and air conditioning) proffesional

Dates Employed May 2006 - Aug 2016

Employment Duration 10 yrs 3 mos

I was working in a variety of positions within the HVAC industry

- Compact Air Handling Units (AHU) project manager (~ 1 year)
- AHU technical support (~1 year)
- HVAC designer (~5 years)
- Energy modeler for LEED certification (~ 1 year)
- Technical superviser on site (~1 years)
- Ventilation systems installer (~1 year)

Projects

- Air handling units selection engine powered by machine learning
- <https://gitlab.com/remak-dva/docker-freecad-cli>
- < https://gitlab.com/zhukovgreen/pozemky> This is how I bought my home

- <<u>https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/gcal time track tg bot</u>> This is how I used to track my time
- Dog breed identification
- https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/dog-project/blob/master/dog-app.ipvnb
- Reinforcement learning
- https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/machine-learning/blob/submission/smartcab/projects/ smartcab/smartcab/agent.py>
- Supervise learning problem < https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/UMLND/blob/ d7a1326247705cac90120c266ca6296e7b19e257/finding donors/finding donors.ipynb>
- PyTorch, transfer learning https://github.com/ZhukovGreen/pytorch-scholarship- challenge>
- Unsupervised learning problem
- <https://qithub.com/ZhukovGreen/machine-learning/blob/submission/costumer-seqments/</pre> projects/customer segments/customer segments.ipynb>

Education ## Udacity

Degree Name Nano-degree Field Of Study Machine Learning Grade Nano-degree Dates attended or expected graduation 2016 - 2018

< https://www.udacity.com/course/machine-learning-engineer-nanodegree--nd009>

Stanford University Online

Degree Name Online Education Field Of Study CS229: Machine Learning Grade NA Dates attended or expected graduation 2016 - 2017

I passed through all lectures videos and keynotes, resolved all assignments. Course syllabus: < http://cs229.stanford.edu/syllabus.html>

Donbass State Academy of Civil Engineering and Architecture

Degree Name Master's Degree Field Of Study Mechanical Engineering (HVAC) Grade M.Sc. in heating, ventilation, air conditioning systems Dates attended or expected graduation 2002 - 2008

Courses

Udacity: PyTorch Scholarship Challenge from Facebook A vast amount of different courses at Udemy, such as data structures and algorithms, PyTorch Reinforcement learning etc.

Languages

Russian - native English - good proffesional level Czech - good proffesional level

Social profiles

- GitHub < https://github.com/zhukovgreen>
- GitLab < https://gitlab.com/zhukovgreen>
- StackOverflow < https://stackoverflow.com/users/4351027/artem-zhukov>
- Twitter < https://twitter.com/zhukovareen>
- LinkedIn < https://www.linkedin.com/in/artem-zhukov-0556b422/